Visual AIDS Artist Files
Visual AIDS Archive
- John Lesnick (1953–2003)
  John Lesnick was born in 1953. He studied art education and printmaking at SUNY Oneonta, SUNY Buffalo, and Indiana University. He worked primarily in photography, photo screen prints, and photo imagery on ceramic tiles and was widely exhibited. His work is in the collections of the Museum of Modern Aart and the Brooklyn Museum, among others. He passed away in 2003.
  John Lesnick first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain prints of artwork, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, an artist's biography, CVs, press clippings, correspondence, calendar submission materials, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1980-2003.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/john-lesnick
  - Box 32, Folder 1 (Box 32)
  - Box 32, Folder 2 (Box 32)
  - Box 32, Folder 3 (Box 32)
- Fran Lewis (1953–2006)
  Fran Lewis was born in 1953 in LeFlore County, Oklahoma and grew up in Santa Barbara, California. She lived and worked in the Bay Area for over 25 years, working in a wide variety of mediums, including acrylic, watercolors, pastels and silk, as well as photography, mixed media sculpture and historical reproduction. She passed away in 2006.
  Fran Lewis first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain an exhibition announcement, CVs, calendar submission materials, press clippings, an artist's statement, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1996-2005.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/fran-lewis
  - Box 32, Folder 4 (Box 32)
- Samuel Lewis (b. 1953)
  Samuel Fleming Lewis was born in 1953 in Los Angeles, CA. He studied figure drawing, fine arts, interior design, and environmental design at Otis Art Institute, Los Angeles City College, and the University of California Extension. He has worked in architecture and interior design while making his mixed media collage works and drawings. His work has been exhibited in California.
  Samuel Lewis first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain CVs, artist's statements, correspondence, a photograph of artist, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1995-1997.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/samuel-fleming-lewis
  - Box 32, Folder 5 (Box 32)
- Marc Lida (1957–1992)
  Marc Lida was born in 1957 in New York City. He was educated at the Brooklyn Museum Art School, SUNY Purchase, and Parsons School of Design. His work was exhibited in New York, New Jersey, and Connecticut. He passed away in 1992.
  Materials pertaining to Marc Lida were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997 by David Lida. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, a scan of artwork, photographic prints of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1982-1999.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/marc-lida
  - Box 32, Folder 6 (Box 32)
- Edward T. Lightner (b. 1960)
  Edward Lightner was born in 1960 in Bakersfield, California. He studied at California State University and University of South Florida. His work has been exhibited in California, Florida, and New York. His work is an ongoing contemplation of his views on life and death. He lives in California.
  Edward Lightner first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, exhibition catalogs, CVs, artist's statements, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, calendar submission materials, press clippings, CD with images of art, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1998-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/edward-lightner
  - Box 32, Folder 8 (Box 32)
  - Box 33, Folder 1 (Box 33)
  - Box 33, Folder 2 (Box 33)
- Elliott Linwood (b. 1956)
  Elliott Linwood was born in 1956 in Massachusetts. He was educated at NYU, University of Chicago, San Francisco State University and the New College of California School of Law, receiving degrees in various fields, as well as teaching at San Francisco State University. His work has been exhibited and won awards throughout the US.
  Elliott Linwood first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain exhibition announcements, CDs with images of art, correspondence, CVs, an artist's biography, an artist's statement, press clippings, photographic prints of art, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1991-2004
  https://visualaids.org/artists/elliott-linwood
  - Box 33, Folder 3 (Box 33)
- Kairon Liu (b. 1992)
  Kairon Liu was born in 1992 in Taipei, Taiwan. He graduated from the Department of Graphic Communication at Shih Hsin University. He is an artist, curator, and photographer. His work has won many awards and been exhibited internationally. He has also curated several exhibitions in Taipei.
  Materials pertaining to Kairon Liu include exhibition announcements. This material is dated 2018-2023.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/kairon-liu
  - Box 33, Folder 4 (Box 33)
- Eduardo Lluria-Mirales (b. 1955)
  Eduardo Lluria-Miralles was born in 1955 in Havana, Cuba. He received a BA in biology from Holy Cross College and an MBA in finance from New York University. After a long career on Wall Street he began to focus on his creative work. He works primarily in oil paintings and his work has been exhibited in Florida.
  Eduardo Lluria-Miralles first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain correspondence, an artist's biography, an artist's statement, a CV, press clippings, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1998-2001.
  - Box 33, Folder 9 (Box 33)
- Ronald Lockett (1965–1998)
  Ronald Lockett was born in 1965 in Bessemer, Alabama. He began making art full time in his early twenties. He was mentored by his older cousin, the artist Thornton Dial. By the time of his death, he had produced over 350 works, primarily mixed media sculptures and paintings. He passed away in 1998.
  Materials pertaining to Ronald Lockett include an exhibition program and an exhibition checklist. These materials are dated 2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/ronald-lockett
  - Box 69, Folder 6 (Box 69)
- Charles Ryan Long (b. 1979)
  Charles Ryan Long was born in 1979 in Chicago. His work includes painting, sculpture, installation, and mixed media art.
  Charles Long first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2012. They contain exhibition announcements and copies of original artwork. These materials are dated 2012-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/charles-long
  - Box 33, Folder 6 (Box 33)
- Antonio Lopez (1943–1987)
  Antonio Lopez was born in 1943 in Utuado, Puerto Rico. His family moved to New York City when he was seven. He helped his parents, who worked as a seamstress and a mannequin maker, inspiring a lifelong love of fashion. He went to Traphagen School of Fashion on the weekends as a teenager and later to the Fashion Institute of Technology, going on to illustrate fashions for major publications. He made great strides in exploring and representing the racialized body in the world of high fashion. His imagery helped to develop and underscore a new canon of beauty in the 1970s and 80s. He passed away in 1987.
  Materials pertaining to Antonio Lopez inlude an article and book publication materials. These materials are dated 2004-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/antonio-lopez
  - Box 69, Folder 7 (Box 69)
  - Box C, Folder 12 (Box C)
- Dean Loren (b. 1958)
  Dean Loren was born in 1958 in Washington, DC. He received a BS in Chemistry from the University of Maryland and a JD from Fordham University. His work has been exhibited in New York and represents a variety of mediums, including video, painting, illustration, and sculpture.
  Dean Loren first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2016. They contain correspondence, a CV, and a list of images as part of grant materials. These materials are dated 2016.
  - Box 33, Folder 7 (Box 33)
- Gin Louie (1947–1994)
  Gin Louie was born in 1953 in Troy, New York. He was raised by a Chinese American family in Chinatown. He taught at the Lower East Side Printshop and produced several public art projects. His artwork was informed by his study in printmaking techniques. He passed away in 1994.
  Materials pertaining to Gin Louie were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001 by John Lesnick. They contain exhibition announcements, a CV, correspondence, an artist's biography, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1993-2004.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/gin-louie
  - Box 34, Folder 1 (Box 34)
- Michael Lownie (b. 1952)
  Michael Lownie was born in 1952 in Buffalo, New York. He received a BFA in painting from Daeman College n Amherst, New York, and later moved to and studied in San Francisco. His work has been exhibited widely in the US, primarily in California and New York.
  Michael Lownie first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2004. They contain CDs with images of art, exhibition announcements, CVs, artist's statements, image lists, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 2004-2009
  https://visualaids.org/artists/michael-lownie
  - Box 34, Folder 2 (Box 34)
- Charles Lum (1958–2021)
  Charles Lum was born in 1958 in Rockville Centre, New York. He received a BA in Film Studies from Carleton College in Northfield, Minnesota, and an MFA in Photography from the Art Institute of Chicago. His practice includes documentary and narrative filmmaking, often with sexually explicit content, as well as photography and performance. His work has been exhibited internationally. He passed away in 2021.
  Charles Lum first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2006. They contain CDs with images of art, ephemera, exhibition announcements, correspondence, a CV, periodicals, a publication, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2004-2022.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/charles-lum
  - Box 34, Folder 4 (Box 34)
- Peter Madero III (b. 1953)
  Peter Madero III was born in 1954 in New York City. He studied at Rutgers University. He worked as a commercial photographer for many years in addition to his artistic practice. He also owned a gallery in Midtown with a specialization in Puerto Rican art.
  Peter Madero III first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain correspondence, exhibition announcements, a CV, calendar submission materials, CDs with images of art, calendars of photography, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1998-2007.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/peter-madero-iii
  - Box 34, Folder 6 (Box 34)
  - Box 34, Folder 7 (Box 34)
- Joseph Magliaro (b. 1954)
  Joseph Magliaro was born in 1954 in Newark, New Jersey. He was educated at the Art Students League in New York and worked with various teachers on various scholarships. He works primarily in painting, both realistic and abstract.
  Joseph Magliaro first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain a photographic print of artwork, calendar submission materials, an artist's biography, an artist's statement, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1998-2001.
  - Box 34, Folder 8 (Box 34)
- Cornelius Manunure (b. 1963)
  Cornelius Manunure was born in 1963. He studied art, community development, and business studies. He is a sculptor and works primarily in Zimbabwe.
  Cornelius Manunure first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000. This collection includes a CV. This material is dated 2000-2001.
  - Box 34, Folder 9 (Box 34)
- Hamlet Manzueta (1964-2019)
  Hamlet Manzueta was born in 1964 in the Dominican Republic. He studied graphic design and fashion industry at the Fashion Insitute of Technology in New York. His painting, photography, and illustration work has been exhibited in New York and the Dominican Republic. He passed away in 2019.
  Hamlet Manzueta first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain correspondence, photographic prints of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2001-2002.
  - Box 34, Folder 10 (Box 34)
- Robert Mapplethorpe (1946–1989)
  Robert Mapplethorpe was born in 1946 in New York. He received a BFA from Pratt Institute where he produced artwork of various media, mainly collage. His shift to photography happened in the mid-1970s. He took his first photographs of Patti Smith with a polaroid camera and later became known for his portraits of an array of unique people, including many celebrities. His work has been exhibited internationally both during his life and posthumously. He is considered to be among the most important American photographers of the latter half of the 20th century. He passed away in 1989.
  Materials pertaining to Robert Mapplethorpe include promotional materials, correspondence, and press clippings. These materials are dated 1998-2000.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/robert-mapplethorpe
  - Box 35, Folder 1 (Box 35)
- Thom Markee (b. 1974)
  Thom Markee was born in 1974 in Maine. He attended the Art Institute of Boston and studied art, including figure drawing and sculpture. He continued to draw and paint, creating most of his work from 1999-2002. His work has been exhibited in New York and Massachusetts.
  Thom Markee first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain exhibition announcements, photographic prints, CVs, artist's statements, an artist's biography, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2002-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/thom-markee
  - Box 35, Folder 2 (Box 35)
- (William) Neil Marshal (1950–2007)
  William Neil Marshall was born in 1950 in Ontario, Canada. He was educated at the University of Toronto in art history, philosophy, and renaissance studies. His work has been exhibited widely in the US and Canada.
  William Neil Marshall first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying slide list. These materials are dated 1977-2006.
  - Box 35, Folder 3 (Box 35)
- Dani Marti (b. 1963)
  Dani Marti was born in 1963 in Barcelona, Spain. He was educated in Barcelona, Sydney, New York, and Glasgow. His work has been exhibited widely internationally.
  Dani Marti first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2012. They contain a DVD of work, a CV, and an artist's biography. These materials are dated 2010-2012.
  - Box 35, Folder 4 (Box 35)
- Greg Maskwa (b. 1953)
  Greg Maskwa was born in 1953 in Canada. He studied painting and textile design at Cambrian College of Applied Art. He then moved to San Francisco in 1972 where he began exhibiting art. He moved to New York in 1979 and worked as a freelance illustrator and writer. His work was been published and exhibited widely and internationally. He passed away in 2023.
  Greg Maskwa first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain a CD with images of art, photographic prints, ephemera, exhibition materials, an artist's biography, artist's statements, press clippings, calendar submission materials, correspondence, memorial materials, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1979-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/greg-maskwa
  - Box 35, Folder 6 (Box 35)
- Quenttel Mathis (b. 1960)
  Quenttel Mathis was born in 1960 in Illinois. He was educated at the New School and Alliance Francaise. He has worked as a photostylist and window display fabricator in New York.
  Quenttel Mathis first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2010. This collection contains a CV. These materials are dated 2010.
  - Box 35, Folder 7 (Box 35)
- Frank Maya (1950–1995)
  Frank Maya was born in 1950 in Queens, New York and grew up in Babylon, Long Island. He studied at Hofstra University and after graduating, began a career as a singer, songwriter, and poet, appearing extensively in Manhattan. In the 1980s he redefined himself as a performance artist and later a stand-up comedian. He starred in his own half-hour special on Comedy Central. As a visual artist, he worked primarily in illustration. He passed away in 1995.
  Materials pertaining to Frank Maya include performance announcements and obituaries. These materials are dated 1987-1995.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/frank-maya
  - Box 35, Folder 8 (Box 35)
- Amber McCarthy (b. 1968)
  Amber McCarthy was born in 1968 in Galesburg, Illinois. Her artwork is primarily pencil drawings and acrylic paintings. Her work has been exhibited in New York.
  Amber McCarthy first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain grant application materials, photocopies of illustrations, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1998-2003.
  - Box 35, Folder 10 (Box 35)
- James Ray McCleskey VI (1938–1997)
  James Ray McCleskey VI was born in 1938 in Colon, Panama to American parents. He attended the Suwanee Military Academy and was self-taught in photography. He passed away in 1996.
  Materials related to James Ray McCleskey VI were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000 by Margaret McCleskey. They contain correspondence. These materials are dated 2000.
  - Box 35, Folder 11 (Box 35)
- Leon McCutcheon (b. 1959)
  Leon McCutcheon was born in 1959. He works primarily in watercolor paintings. He lives and works in New York City.
  Materials pertaining to Leon McCutcheon include a photographic print of artwork.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/leon-mccutcheon
  - Box 35, Folder 12 (Box 35)
- Joyce McDonald (b. 1951)
  Joyce McDonald was born in 1951 in Brooklyn, New York. She is a multidisciplinary artist best know for her figurative sculptures. She is a speaker for her church's AIDS ministry and works closely with her community. Her work has been exhibited in New York and London, and is in the collection of the Brooklyn Museum and the Hammer Museum, among others. In 2021, she was the first artist to join West Elm's ceramic residency in Brooklyn.
  Joyce McDonald first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, photographic prints of artwork, ephemera, CVs, artist's biographies, calendar submission materials, artist's statements, image lists. Postcards from the Edge submission materials, press releases, press clippings, event programs, testimonials, newsletters, periodicals, CDs with work, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1998-2020.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/joyce-mcdonald
  - Box 36, Folder 1 (Box 36)
  - Box 36, Folder 2 (Box 36)
  - Box C, Folder 10 (Box C)
- Preston McGovern (b. 1951)
  Preston McGovern was born in 1951 in Wilmington, Delaware. He received a BA from Tusculum College in Tusculum, Tennessee. His work is in mixed media, collage, and sculpture, and has been exhibited in New York.
  Preston McGovern first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, image lists, calendar submission materials, press clippings, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1982-2000.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/preston-mcgovern
  - Box 36, Folder 3 (Box 36)
- Kathryn McGuinness (b. 1958–2015)
  Kathryn McGuinness was born in 1958 in New York City. A self-taught artist, Kathryn's work on paper and canvas was a source of joy for her and those around her. She passed away in 2015.
  Kathryn McGuiness first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2013. They contain correspondence and grant application materials. These materials are dated 2013-2015.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/kathryn-mcguinness
  - Box 36, Folder 4 (Box 36)
- Andrew McPhail (b. 1961)
  Andrew McPhail was born in 1961 in Calgary, Alberta, Canada. He received both a BFA and MFA from York University in Toronto. Beginning with illustration on mylar, his art evolved to three dimensional work, performance, and painting. His work has been exhibited internationally.
  Andrew McPhail first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2008. They contain a CD with images of art, exhibition announcements, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, CVs, an artist's statement, and press releases. These materials are dated 2006-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/andrew-mcphail
  - Box 36, Folder 6 (Box 36)
- Steven Mendelson (1958–1995)
  Steven Mendelson was born in 1958 in Highland Park, Illinois. A lifelong artist, he studied at Rhode Island School of Design. He worked as an illustrator for the Washington Post and his work appeared in Europe, India, Latin America, and Japan. He illustrated four books for humor columnist Art Buchwald, and wrote and illustrated children's books. He passed away in 1995.
  Materials pertaining to Steven Mendelson were donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000 by Carol Mendelson. They contain a CV, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1988-2001.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/steven-mendelson
  - Box 37, Folder 1 (Box 37)
- Lucas Michael (b. 1965)
  Lucas Michael was born in 1965 in Buenos Aires, Argentina. He was educated at the Rhode Island School of Design. His work in photography, sculpture, installation, video, and other various media has been shown internationally and featured in multiple publications. He lives and works in New York.
  Lucas Michael first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2012 and again in 2021. They contain correspondence, a CD with images of art, a CV, an artist's biography, ephemera, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, and artist's statements. These materials are dated 2003-2021.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/lucas-michael
  - Box 37, Folder 4 (Box 37)
- Karl Michalak (1958–1997)
  Karl Michalak was born in 1958 in Binghamton, New York. He received an MFA from Columbia University. He was an artist, cartoonist, art therapist, writer, film critic, performer, and political activist. He passed away in 1997.
  Materials pertaining to Karl Michalak were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Michael Sturza. They contain ephemera, an artist's biography, an artist's statement, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1989-1998.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/karl-michalak
  - Box 37, Folder 5 (Box 37)
- Tiger Milner (b. 1960)
  Tiger Milner was born in 1960. He is a fine artist, performance artist, graphic designer, display designer, and writer. He has a BA in painting from Florida Gulf Coast University and an MFA in Media Design from Full Sail University. His work includes painting, mixed media, collage, and print making.
  Tiger Milner first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2013. This collection includes a CD with images of art. This material is dated 2013-2014.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/tiger-milner
  - Box 37, Folder 7 (Box 37)
- Greg Mitchell (b. 1957)